This is what I get in return for 30 years of service for my company?
这就是我为公司辛苦30年的回报？
And they send some yo-yo like you in here,
他们就派了你这么个傻瓜
to try to tell me that I'm out of a job?
来通知我被炒鱿鱼了？
They should be telling you you're out of a job.
真正该滚蛋的应该是你
You have a lot of gall, coming in here and firing your No.1 producer.
你们可真够狠心的，居然炒掉 最优秀的员工
You're going to go home and make more money than you've ever made in your life
回到家你会赚的比以往都多
and I'm going to go home without a pay cheque. Fuck you.
而我就这么两手空空回去 去你妈的
I guess you leave me dumbfounded. I don't know where this is coming from.
你把我都说懵了 我不明白为什么
How am I meant to go back as a man and explain to my wife I lost my job?
我怎么作为一个男人回去 和我老婆说我失业了？
On a stress level, I've heard that losing your job is like a death in the family.
从压力角度说，我听说 失业也就意味着家庭的终结
But personally, I feel more like
但是，我个人觉得
the people I worked with were my family and I died.
我的同事都是我的家人 而我死了
I can't afford to be unemployed.
我无法承受失业的压力
I have a house payment, I have children.
我有房贷要还，我还有孩子要养
I don't know how you can live with yourself,
我不清楚你自己怎么谋生
but I'm sure that you'll find a way while the rest of us are suffering.
但我知道你能找到出路 而剩下的我们却在受苦
Who the fuck are you, man?
你他妈的到底是谁？
Excellent question. Who the fuck am I?
问得好，我到底是谁？
Poor Steve has worked here for seven years.
可怜的Steve在这儿工作7年了
He's never had a meeting with me before or passed me in the hall,
他从来没和我开过会 也没在走廊碰见过我
or told me a story in the break room.
或是在休息室和我聊过天
That's because I don't work here.
那是因为我就不在这儿上班
I work for another company that lends me out to pussies like Steve's boss
我的公司派我来 给像Steve的老板这样的人帮忙
who don't have the balls to sack their own employees,
因为他们没有胆量 解雇他们自己的雇员
in some cases for good reason. People do crazy shit when they get fired.
有时候人们被炒鱿鱼时 会由于感觉没有道理而变得疯狂
Did I do something wrong?
我做错什么了吗？
I mean, is there something I could do differently here?
有什么我可以改进的地方吗？
This is not an assessment of your productivity. Don't take this personally.
这不是对你能力的评定 不要以为是针对个人的
Don't take it personally.
不是针对个人的
Steven, I want you to review this packet.
Steven，好好看看这份材料
Take it seriously. I think you're gonna find a lot of good answers in here.
认真看看，你会找到很多好的答案
I'm sure this is gonna be very helpful - a packet.
我相信这个会很有帮助，一份材料
Thank you... A packet.
谢谢你...一份材料
Well, anybody who ever built an empire or changed the world sat where you are right now.
任何建立自己帝国或者改变世界的伟人 也都经历过你现在的处境
And it's because they sat there they were able to do it.
就是因为经历了挫折 他们才能做的更精彩
That's the truth.
这是真的
I'm gonna need your keycard.
你的出入证需要交还
Great. OK.
好了
Now, I want you to take the day, go get together your personal things, then tomorrow
我希望你今天之内收拾好 你的个人物品，然后明天
you get yourself some exercise. You go out for a jog,
做些锻炼，出去跑跑步
you give yourself some routines and pretty soon you find your legs.
给你自己找点儿事做 很快你就能适应新的生活
How do I get in touch with you? - Don't worry, we'll be in touch soon.
- 我怎么和你联系？ - 别担心，我们很快会联系
This is just the beginning.
这只是个开始
I'll never see Steve again.
我再不会见到Steve了
To know me is to fly with me. This is where I live.
要认识我就要和我一起坐飞机 这是我生活的地方
When I run my card,
当我刷我的卡时
the system automatically prompts the desk clerk to greet me with this exact statement:
系统会自动提示接待人员 用这句话欢迎我
Pleasure to see you again, Mr Bingham.
很高兴再次见到您，Bingham先生
It's these kinds of systemised friendly touches that keep my world in orbit.
就是这些系统化的示好行为 让我的世界运转自如
All the things you probably hate about travelling -
所有可能导致你 讨厌旅行的东西
the recycled air, the artificial lighting, the digital juice dispensers,
循环空气，人工灯光 数字果汁机
the cheap sushi - are warm reminders that I'm home.
廉价的寿司，都在提醒我 我到家了
Do you want the cancer?
来罐饮料吗，先生？
The what? - Do you want the cancer?
- 什么？ - 来罐饮料吗，先生？
The cancer?
癌症？
The can...sir? - Oh, no. I'm fine, thank you.
- 这个饮料...先生？ - 哦，不用了，谢谢
How much does your life weigh?
你的生活有多重？
Imagine for a second that you're carrying a backpack.
想象你背着一个背包
I want you to feel the straps on your shoulders. Feel 'em?
感觉一下肩上的背带 感觉到了吗？
Now I want you to pack it with all the stuff that you have in your life.
现在装些你生活里的东西进去
Start with the little things,
从小东西开始
the things on shelves and in drawers the knick-knacks, the collectibles.
架子上和抽屉里的 小装饰，收藏品
Feel the weight as that adds up.
感觉一下这些加起来的重量
Then you start adding larger stuff - clothes, table-top appliances, lamps, linens...
然后开始放一些大件 衣服，桌面用具，台灯，纸张
your TV...
还有你的电视
The backpack should be getting pretty heavy now. And you go bigger.
背包现在应该很重了吧 接着装
Your couch, bed, your kitchen table. Stuff it all in there.
你的沙发，床，餐桌 统统塞进来
Your car, get it in there.
你的汽车，也塞进来
Your home, whether it's a studio apartment or a two-bedroomed house.
你的房子，不管是单间的公寓房 还是两居室
I want you to stuff it all into that backpack.
把所有的东西都塞进这个背包
Now try to walk.
然后试着走两步
It's kind of hard, isn't it?
很困难，是吧？
This is what we do to ourselves on a daily basis
这就是我们按照日常准则 对自己所做的
We weigh ourselves down until we can't even move. And make no mistake...
我们不断给自己加压，直到走不动 还不能犯错
moving is living.
移动才是生活
Now, I'm gonna set that backpack on fire. What do you want to take out of it?
现在，我要把这个背包烧了 你们想要拿什么出来？
Photos?
照片？
Photos are for people who can't remember. Drink some ginkgo and let the photos burn.
照片是给那些记性不好的人用的 喝点银杏茶，把照片烧了吧 （有资料称银杏可改善记忆力）
In fact, let everything burn and imagine waking up tomorrow with nothing.
其实，你可以把所有都烧了 想象你明早起来一无所有
It's kind of exhilarating, isn't it?
很爽，是吧？
Welcome back, Mr Bingham.
欢迎回来，Bingham先生
Ryan Bingham's office. - You have me in a Dodge Stratus in Kansas City.
- 这里是Ryan Bingham办公室 - 你在堪萨斯给我弄了一辆道奇Stratus
They were out of all full-size sedans. - Did you try...
- 他们没有标准尺寸的轿车了 - 你没试着...
Yes, I reminded them of your remarkable No.1 Gold Club status in years in the program.
试了，我跟他们说了你在这个节目 数年的金牌会员身份
They are literally moving mountains to see you in a Sebring.
他们下次一定给弄一辆Sebring
Fair enough. Any other messages? - Er...your sister Kara called.
- 好吧，有其他事吗？ - 嗯...你姐姐Kara打过电话
Needs to speak urgently about your sister's wedding.
迫切需要和你说说 你妹妹的婚礼
I told her you were mid-air, and not even I knew your destination.
我跟她说你在天上 我也不知道你要去哪儿
Well done. - You got an invitation to speak at GoalQuest in Vegas.
- 很好 - 还有一个在拉斯维加斯的GoalQuest演讲的邀请
GoalQuest 20?
GoalQuest 20？
Every once in a while, I do speaking engagements, motivational stuff. But GoalQuest?
偶尔，我会做一些预约演讲 激励一类的东西，可是GoalQuest？
We're talking major Tony Robbins shit.
Tony Robbins的那些垃圾 （Tony Robbins，激励大师）
It's got a hologram on it. They're calling it Dos Equis.
上面还有个全息图像 他们叫Dos Equis
All right, I'll check in. - I've got Craig Gregory for you.
- 好吧，我会去的 - 我给你接到Craig Gregory那儿
Wait...ah. Fuck.
等...该死的
How is my little road warrior?
怎么样，我征战的勇士？
Hey, 20 minutes from boarding into a world of bliss.
嘿，还有20分钟进入幸福世界
Real good numbers out of Phoenix, Ry guy.
凤凰城的任务干的不错 我的Ryan
You know that Big Auto is about to cut another 10K by the end of the month?
你知道汽车巨头这月底之前 又要裁员1万吗？
No kidding. - Christmas came early.
- 不是吧 - 圣诞节来早了
I wish you could be in five places, but I need you here in Omaha this week. Alright?
我希望你能去5个地方 不过这周我需要你回奥马哈来，好吧
I thought you needed me everywhere. - We got something real big, a real game changer.
- 我还以为你需要我去所有的地方 - 我们有些重大变化，有个变革者
What are we talking about here?
什么意思？
You'll see. Today I took my first crap in two weeks - hallelujah.
你会明白的，今天我下了两周内 的第一注，哈利路亚
That's me hanging up on you. - Great, love that sound.
- 我才是让你担心的那个 - 很好，就喜欢你这句
Are you satisfied with Maestro?
你对Maestro还满意吗？ （汽车租赁公司）
Yeah, I am.
是的
A little stingy with their miles. I like Hertz.
他们的里程算的很严 我喜欢Hertz
No, Hertz keeps its vehicles too long. If a car has over 20,000 miles, I won't drive it.
不，Hertz的车太旧了 我从不开里程超过20万公里的车
Maestro doesn't instant checkout. I like the park-and-go.
Maestro不能即时结账 我喜欢即停即走
Hertz doesn't guarantee navigation. - You don't seem like a girl who needs directions.
- Hertz还不是每辆车都有导航仪 - 你可不像需要导航仪的女孩
I hate asking for directions. - That's why I get a nav.
我讨厌问路，所以我才需要导航仪
That new outfit, Colonial, isn't bad.
那个新公司，Colonial，还不错
Is that a joke? - Yes.
- 你开玩笑的吧？ - 是的
Their kiosk placement blows. - They never have available upgrades.
- 他们的停车场很烂 - 而且从来没有升级
Basically, it's a fleet of shit boxes. I don't know how they're still in business.
基本就是一堆破盒子 我真不明白他们怎么还没破产
I'm Ryan. - I'm Alex.
- 我叫Ryan - 我叫Alex
Aww...Maplewood card. How dare you bring that into this palace?
哦...Maplewood酒店的卡 你怎么好意思拿到这儿来？
Hilton offers equal value and better food but the Maplewood gives out warm cookies at check-in.
Hilton的价格相同，食物也更好 可Maplewood入住时会送点心
I'm a sucker for simulated hospitality.
我对虚伪的好客很着迷
There's an industry term for that. It's a mixture of faux and homey - faumey.
其实对这种情况有个专业术语 是“仿”和“家”的结合，叫“仿家”
Oh, my God. I wasn't sure this actually existed.
哦，天哪 我都不知道这卡确实存在
This is the American Airlines... - It's a Concierge Key, yeah.
- 这是美国航空公司... - 至尊贵宾卡，是的
What is that, carbon fibre? - Graphite.
- 什么材料，碳纤维？ - 石墨纤维
Oh, I love the weight. - I was pretty excited the day that bad boy came in.
- 哦，我喜欢这质感 - 拿到这张卡的时候我很激动
I'll say. I put up pretty pedestrian numbers. 60 thou a year, domestic.
没错，我也攒了不少里程数 每年6万，国内的
That's not bad. - Don't patronise me.
- 不错啊 - 别鄙视我了
What's your total? - It's a personal question.
- 你攒了多少了？ - 这是隐私
Pleace. - And we hardly know each other.
- 别这样 - 而且我们还不熟
Show some hubris. Come on, impress me.
狂妄点儿，快，吓吓我
I bet it's huge. - You have no idea.
- 我猜肯定是天文数字 - 你想象不到的
How big?
有多大
What is it, this big? This big? - I don't want to brag.
- 到底多大，这么大？还是这么大？ - 我不想吹嘘
Oh, come on! Come on.
喔，快，说出来听听
Let's just say I have a number in mind. I haven't hit it yet.
我心里有个目标，现在还没到
This is pretty fucking sexy. - Hope it doesn't cheapen our relationship.
- 这卡可真性感 - 希望它不会让我们的关系变得低俗
We're two people who get turned on by Elite Status. I think cheap is our starting point.
我们两个追求精英身份的人 我想低俗是我们的起点
There's nothing cheap about loyalty.
忠诚没什么低俗的
We came up with this master plan, which was for me...
我们想出了这个计划，给我...
...to put gauze, to put bandages on both my hands.
双手缠上纱布和绷带
Then we got on the plane, transatlantic, flying to erm...Zurich.
然后我们上了飞机 越洋航班，飞去，呃...苏黎世
I waited till it was dark, and I walked up to the bathroom with her.
我等到天黑 然后和她去了洗手间
Everybody was watching the movie and I was like...
大家都在看电影，而我...
Opened up, went inside. She opened the door for me, and came in like she was gonna help me.
开门，进去，她给我开的门 做出要帮我的样子
We gave it our best shot. It wasn't great. But it was fun. It was tricky.
我们用尽全力，不是很棒 但很有意思，很微妙
Give me some details. - It's not so easy. Have you tried it?
- 说点儿细节 - 不好说，你以前试过吗
It's not so easy. - Yes, I have.
- 不好形容 - 当然，我试过
Really? - Really.
- 真的？ - 真的
You've done that? - I have done that.
- 你真做过？ - 我真做过
On a transatlantic flight? - On a domestic flight - regional, actually.
- 在越洋航班上？ - 国内航班，实际上是地方航线
At night-time? - Daytime.
- 晚上吗？ - 白天？
What? - How do you do that?
- 怎么了？ - 你们怎么做的？
Oh, I'm really flexible.
我柔韧性很好
Look. Ohh.
瞧瞧
Ah, I should throw these out.
我真该把这些扔了
We can always use that room with the ice machine.
我们可以一直用那个 有制冰机的房间
Look.
听着
Good call on that towel rack.
毛巾架那段真棒
I like how you burritoed me in the sofa cushions.
我喜欢你把我压在沙发垫上
I was improvising.
我即兴表演的
Shame we didn't make it to the closet.
真可惜我们没在壁橱里做
We got to do this again. - Oh, yeah.
- 我们得再来一次 - 确实
I'm in Newark on the 12th, Modesto on the 13th...
我12号在纽瓦克，13号在莫德斯托
Oklahoma City on the 15th...
15号在俄克拉荷马城
Any Southwest? I'll be swinging by Albuquerque week of the 16th.
有西南部的吗？我从16号开始 要在阿尔伯克基呆一周
No, I'm in Florida on the 20th. - Fort Lauderdale?
- 不，我20号在佛罗里达 - 劳德代尔堡？
Miami. - That's nothing. - 40 minutes.
- 迈阿密？ - 40分钟就能到
I should probably go back to my room so I can wake up in my bed.
我得回我房间了 要不明早就不在我床上起来了
I think that would be the ladylike thing to do.
我以为那是贵妇才这样
Nice meeting you. - A pleasure.
- 很高兴遇到你 - 我也是
Hello?
喂？
Hey, Ryan, how you holding up?
嘿，Ryan，你还好吧？
Every family has one person who keeps the genealogy in check.
每家都会有个人专门 负责维系整个家族
That's my sister Kara - the glue.
我家就是我姐姐Kara 就像胶水一样
Fine. You and the kids?
还好，你和孩子们呢？
Missy's outstanding, Matthew made varsity. How's the road?
Missy成绩不错，Matthew也进了校队 你的旅途怎么样？
Couldn't be better.
再好不过
Good. So, Ryan?
很好，那么Ryan？
Yeah?
什么？
I didn't even want to ask you this, because I know how you are about doing things for others.
我也不想问你 我知道你总是忙着给别人帮忙
But we're coming up on three weeks to go to Julie's wedding and we could really use your help.
可还有三周就到Julie的婚礼了 我们需要你的帮忙
Yeah?
什么事？
We've been sending people these kits,
我们在给亲友们发这些套件
so they can print out photos of Julie and Jim on cardbord,
希望他们可以印一些 Julie和Jim的纸板像
and then take photos of them in interesting places, like that gnome in the French movie.
然后在一些名胜古迹给他们照相
Why?
为什么？
Because it's Julie's wedding and she thinks it would be fun. Does it matter why?
因为这是Julie的婚礼，她觉得很有意思 原因很重要吗？
How is Julie?
Julie怎么样？
Would you call her. She thinks you've turned to butter.
给她打个电话吧 她以为你都消失了
You're awfully isolated how you live. - Isolated? I'm surrounded.
- 你生活的太孤立了 - 孤立？我周围都是人
So your assistant said you were gonna be in Vegas.
你秘书说你要去拉斯维加斯
Did he?
他这么说的？
Can you get a photo of the cut-out in front of the Luxor pyramid?
你能在Luxor金字塔前给Julie的 纸板像照张相吗
The place is a shithole. Nobody stays there.
那地方就是个垃圾 没人愿意去那儿
Jesus, Ryan, I'm not asking you to check in. Can you just take a stupid photo?
Ryan，我不是请你去那儿住下来 你能就照张照片吗？
I'll try my best.
我尽力吧
Thank you for trying your best.
谢谢你的尽力
Last year, I spent 322 days on the road,
去年，我有322天在路上
which means I had to spend 43 miserable days at home.
也就是说还有43天糟糕的日子 得呆在家里
Hey, neighbour.
嘿，邻居
I signed for this while you were gone. - Oh, thanks.
- 我代你签了你的包裹 - 哦，谢谢
I hope it wasn't too much of a bother. - Nah.
- 希望没太麻烦你 - 没有
It's my sister. I haven't met the guy yet. They're getting married.
这是我妹妹，我还没见过这家伙 他们要结婚了
Lots of luck. - I know, right?
- 真幸福 - 是啊
What are you doing tonight? You wanna come over later?
你今晚有空吗？晚点儿过来吧？
Um...I've started seeing somebody.
呃…我在和别人约会了
Oh. OK. Great.
哦，好吧，挺好
Hey, it's good to see you.
嘿，见到你很高兴
You too. - It seems like it's been a while this time.
- 我也是 - 这次好像时间挺长的
I'm thrilled that everyone's back under one roof. Welcome home, boy's.
大家都聚齐了，我简直太激动了 欢迎回家，孩子们
There's been a lot of whispering about why we're here, so let me jump right in.
你们肯定听到了一些传言 我就直入主题了
Retailers are down 20%.
零售业业绩下降了20%
Auto industry is in the dump. Housing market doesn't have a heartbeat.
汽车工业也在下坡路 房地产市场也快不行了
It is one of the worst times on record for America.
现在是美国历史上最糟糕的时候
This is our moment.
也是我们的机会
Now, last summer, we received a dynamite young woman here from Cornell.
去年夏天，我们招到了这位 从Cornell大学毕业的年轻人
And she had some pretty big ideas that she challenged me with.
她向我提了一些非常大胆的想法
My first reaction was, "Who does this kid think she is?"
我的第一反应是 “这孩子以为她是谁啊？”
But after I gave it a listen, she really knocked me out. So...
可当我听过之后 我很受震动，那么
With a peek into our future, Natalie Keener.
看一眼我们的未来 有请Natalie Keener
If there's one word I want to leave you with today, it's this.
如果今天和大家分享的 只是一个词，那就是它
Glocal?
全球地区化？
Glocal.
全球地区化
Our global must become local.
我们的全球化必须变成地区化
This company keeps 23 people on the road at least 250 days a year.
公司每年要供养23个人 超过250天在路上
It's expensive and it's inefficient
成本很高，而且没效率
When I came to Craig three months ago with this,
我三个月前和Craig说这件事时
he told me, and quite astutely, it's only a problem if you have a solution.
他立马告诉我，只要你能拿出 一个解决方案
Well, today I stand before you with just that.
而今天我给大家的就是 这个解决方案
You all know Ned in reception. Today I'm gonna fire Ned.
你们认识接待处的Ned吧 今天我要辞退Ned
Sorry, Ned. I'm sure HR will hire you back this afternoon.
对不起，Ned，我保证下午人力资源 会把你雇回来的
We'll see about that.
那可不一定啊
Ned could be any employee in any one of our clients' locations worldwide.
Ned可以是我们全球范围内 所有客户的任意一名员工
Strategy packets will be shipped in advance.
策略书会提前送过去
Ned will be given a seat and find one of our transition specialists waiting.
Ned将会面对一位我们的过渡专家
Mr Laskin,
Laskin先生
we're having this conversation as your position is no longer available.
之所以叫您来，是因为我们无法 再提供您的工作机会了
I don't understand. I'm fired?
我不明白，我被炒了？
Hearing the words "You've been let go" is never easy.
听到“你可以走了”这样的话 确实不好受
Change is scary, but consider the following:
变化是令人担忧的，可想想这个：
anybody who ever built an empire or changed the world sat where you are now.
任何建立自己帝国或者改变世界的伟人 也都经历过你现在的处境
And it's because they sat there that they were able to do it.
就是因为经历了挫折 他们才能做的更精彩
That's my fucking line.
那是我的台词
But what happens now?
然后呢？
This is the first step of a process that ends with you in a job that fulfils you.
这是这个过程的第一步 你最终会找到一份满意的工作
Yeah, but how does it work?
好吧，可怎么做呢？
Take the packet in front of you.
拿着你面着的材料
Review it - all the answers you're looking for are inside.
仔细看看 里面有所有你要的答案
Fill out the necessary information and you're on the way to new opportunities.
填上必要的信息 很快你就会有新的机会
Ned, go back to your desk and start putting together your things.
Ned，你可以回你的办公桌 开始收拾东西了
As a favour to me, I'd appreciate it if you didn't spread the news just yet.
帮我个忙，暂时不要 告诉大家这个消息
Panic doesn't help anyone.
恐慌不会有什么好处
I understand.
我明白
Give it up for Ned.
Ned已经被辞退
You can start the morning in Boston, stop in Dallas over lunch,
你可以早上从波士顿开始 午饭的时候在达拉斯
and finish the day in San Francisco. All for the price of a T1 line.
晚上处理旧金山的工作 所需花费只有1条T1通信线路的钱
Our inflated travel budget is eviscerated by 85%.
我们庞大的出差预算 可以减少85%
And more importantly, to you guys on the road,
更重要的是 对于你们这些整天在路上的人
no more Christmases in a hotel in Tulsa, no more hours lost to weather delays.
圣诞节再也不用在塔尔萨的旅馆里过 再也不会因为天气而浪费时间
You get to come home.
你们可以回家了
Tell me you're not taking this seriously.
别说你对这个是认真的
That's why I brought the entire company in from the road,
我才把大家都召回来
because we're not taking it seriously.
因为我们不会认真对待？
There is a methodology to what I do, a reason it works.
我有自己的方法 而它有存在的理由
Coke and IBM have been doing this for years. Familiar with them?
可口可乐和IBM已经这么干了很多年 熟悉吧
Like anything else, it'll take a few months of transition and everybody will settle in.
和别的事情一样，会有几个月的过渡期 然后大家各就各位
Who are you taking off the road? - How are you not getting this?
- 你要让谁停止出差办公？ - 你怎么还不明白？
You are grouned. Everybody's grounded. It's done.
你要呆在公司，大家都是 就这样
What we do here is brutal and it does leave people devastated.
我们所做的事情很残忍 确实会让人们绝望
But there is a dignity to the way I do it.
可我这么做是有尊严在的
By stabbing them in the chest instead of the back, right?
在他们面前告诉他们 而不是在背后捅一刀，好吗？
You wanted to see me? - Well, uhm...
- 有事儿找我？ - 好吧，呃...
You know what? Yeah, come on in. - Great job out there.
- 听着，对，进来 - 刚才讲得不错
Thank you. How's everyone taking it? - Great.
- 谢谢，大家觉得怎么样 - 挺好的
Listen, I admire your...zeal. And I think you have some very good ideas.
听着，我很欣赏你的热情 我也赞同你的主意很好
But you know nothing about the realities of my industry.
可你一点儿也不懂我这行
You can set up an iChat, but you don't know how people think.
你可以建一个网络聊天 可你不知道人们心理怎么想
I minored in psychology. - Nice.
- 我辅修心理学的 - 很好
OK, kiddo, fire me. - Ryan...
- 好吧，孩子，试试炒我鱿鱼 - Ryan
If she's gonna do this regularly, don't you wanna know if she can fire people?
如果将来她要做这行 你不想知道她到底能不能辞退别人？
She's fired Ned. - My dog can fire Ned. Fire me.
- 她刚炒了Ned - 我的狗都能炒了Ned，来，炒了我
You don't need to do this. - No, it's OK. I got this.
- 你不用这么做 - 不，没事儿，我能搞定
Mr Bingham,
Bingham先生
I regret to inform you that your position at this company is no longer available.
很遗憾告诉您 我们无法再提供您的工作
Hm. Who the hell are you?
恩，你到底是谁？
My name is Miss Keener. I'm here today to discuss your future.
我是Keener小姐，我今天来 和你讨论一下你的未来
My future? The only one who can fire me is Craig Gregory.
我的未来？唯一可以炒我鱿鱼的 是Craig Gregory
He hired me to handle this for him. - Handle what? Handle Me?
- 他雇了我来替他做这些 - 做什么？辞退我？
Mr. Gregory hired me, he's the only one who can fire me.
Gregory先生雇佣的我 只有他能辞退我
Know what? I'm gonna go talk to him. - Mr Bingham...
- 我要和他谈 - Bingham先生
No, no. You can't follow me. You're on a computer screen, remember?
不，不，你不能跟着我 你在电脑屏幕前，记得吗？
Ryan.. - Let's try this again. Fire me again.
- Ryan - 我们再来一次，继续辞了我
I just did. - Actually, you didn't. Fire me.
- 我刚辞了你 - 事实上，你没有，辞了我
That's enough. We get it.
行了，我们明白了
Mr Bingham, I'm here to inform you your position is no longer available.
Bingham先生，我来这儿通知您 我们无法再提供您的职位
I'm fired? - Yes, you're fired.
- 我被解雇了？ - 是的，你被解雇了
Never say fired. - You've been let go.
- 千万别说解雇 - 你已经可以离开了
Why?
为什么？
This is a mythical situation. How could I possibly know why?
这是个假设的场景 我怎么知道为什么？
Why doesn't matter, you never know why.
为什么不重要，你从不知道为什么
Don't focus on the why. Rather, spend your energy thinking about your future.
别想着为什么，还不如花点儿精力 想想你的未来
Well, I'm gonna spend my energy on suing you
我会把我的精力花在起诉你上
unless you give me a good reason why you're firing me.
除非你能给我一个解雇我的理由
Mr. Bingham, the reason's not important.
Bingham先生，原因并不重要
You're firing me without grounds? I have a lawsuit.
你毫无缘由就解雇我？ 我可以诉诸法律了
I get what you're trying to say, Ryan. - Don't take this personally, Mr. Bingham.
- 我明白你想说的了，Ryan - 别以为这是针对个人的，Bingham先生
Personally?
针对个人？
This is the most personal situation you are ever gonna enter,
你要踏入的领域 是最针对个人的情况
so before you try to revolutionise my business,
所以在你彻底变革我的事业之前
I'd like to know that you actually know my business.
我希望你了解我的事业
That's a hell of a way to welcome her to the team.
把她请进来让人难以接受啊
Am I the only one that sees that by doing this we're making ourselves irrelevant?
是不是只有我看出来 我们将把自己变得无关紧要
No, frankly, we're making you irrelevant.
不，坦白说 我们会把你变得无关紧要
Nice. - Don't blame me.
- 很好 - 别怪我
Blame high fuel costs, blame insurance premiums, blame technology.
要怪就怪高昂的油价 怪保险费，怪新技术
Watch it. You're a little too young to become a dinosaur.
小心点，你还年轻 别变成被时代抛弃
I'm not a dinosaur. - I want you to show her the ropes.
- 我才不会被时代抛弃 - 我想让你教她点儿规矩
What do I know what goes on here? Get Ferguson to do it.
我怎么知道现在是什么情况？ 让Ferguson去
I'm not talking about here.
我不是说在这儿
No. - Yeah.
- 不 - 是的
You're very confident this girl doesn't know what she's doing. So...
你很清楚这个女孩 不知道她在干什么，所以...
I'm sorry. I don't think a MySpace page qualifies you to rewire a company.
对不起，我不认为一个个人主页 能让你重新部署公司
Here's your chance. Go out, show her the magic, take her through the paces.
这是你的机会，去出差 给她展示一下你的才能，带她走走
I'm not a fucking tour guide.
我可不是个导游
Now here we go. - Bingham, here's the boat.
- 好吧，又来了 - Bingham，这是船
And here's you., Do you want to be in the boat?
这是你，你想上船吗？
Yeah, alone.
是的，一个人
We're ringing the bell, we're rounding everybody up.
我们就要成功，我们在聚拢人
You want to stay out a bit longer, you're welcome, but you will not be alone. Ok?
你想在外面呆久点儿，可以 但你不能是一个人，好吗？
You let me know.
想好了告诉我
Oh, Christ.
我的天啊
What? - Follow me.
- 什么？ - 跟着我
I really like my luggage. That's exactly what it is - luggage.
我很喜欢我的行李箱 那的确是你的――包袱
Know how much time you lose checking in?
知道你在登记时 要浪费多少时间吗
I don't know. Five...10 minutes? - 35 minutes a flight.
- 不知道，5或者10分钟 - 每次航班35分钟
I travel 270 days a year. That's 157 hours.
我一年飞270天 就要浪费157小时
That makes seven days. Willing to throw away an entire week on that?
那就是7天，你想浪费一整周时间 在你的行李上吗？
You don't need this. Sorry, you don't need that.
你不需要这个 对不起，你也不会需要那个
You don't need that. They have neck pillows on the plane.
那个也不需要 飞机上有颈枕
This - they have better ones there. I'll get rid of this.
这个，他们那儿有更好的 我把这个扔了
I can just meet you at security.
我可以在安检那儿找您
Thank you.
谢谢
Bingo - Asians.
太好了，亚洲人
You can't be serious. - Never get behind people with infants.
- 你开玩笑吧 - 千万别跟在抱小孩的人后面
I've never seen a stroller collapse in less than 20 minutes.
有婴儿推车的至少得花20分钟
Old people are worse. They're littered with hidden metal
老人更糟，他们总是会被发现 身上还有金属物体
and they never appreciate how little time they have left on earth.
而且他们从不珍惜 他们在地球上剩下那点儿时间
Five words: randomly selected for additional screening.
随机选择只会增加检查
Asians, they pack light, travel efficiently,
亚洲人，他们行李少，旅行效率高
and they've got a thing for slip-on shoes.
而且他们总是穿轻便鞋
That's racist. - I'm like my mother, I stereotype. It's faster.
- 这是种族主义 - 跟我妈学的，模式化，这样更快
What in your backpack? Ryan Bigham.
你的背包里有什么？ Ryan Bingham
Are you mad at your computer?
你对你的电脑很不满吗
I type with purpose.
我故意的
What is it that you're working on so furiously?
你那么激动地在忙什么呢
I'm building a workflow of firing techniques.
我在画一个解雇技巧的工作流程
It's questions and responses, actions and reactions.
有问题与回答，行为与回应
A script taking you through the steps of firing someone.
一个教你解雇别人的笔记
Who's it for?
给谁用？
Well, theoretically,
理论上
you could put it in the hands of anyone and they'd be downsizing immediately.
你可以给任何一家需要裁员的公司
All you have to do is follow the steps.
你所要做的就是跟着步骤走
Natalie, what is it you think we do here?
Natalie，你觉得我们在干什么？
We prepare the newly-unemployed for the emotional and physical hurdles of job hunting,
我们帮助新失业的人们跨越 求职过程中的情感和实际障碍
while minimising legal blowback.
同时尽量减少法律事务
That's what we're selling. It's not what we're doing.
那是我们所销售的 不是我们所做的
OK, what are we doing? - We are here to make limbo tolerable,
- 好吧，那我们在干什么？ - 我们是让过渡状态更加容易接受
to ferry wounded souls across the river of dread until the point where hope is dimly visible.
帮助受伤的灵魂渡过恐惧的河流 直到希望的曙光出现
Then stop the boat, shove 'em in the water and make 'em swim.
然后停下船，把他们推进水里 让他们自己去游
That's really impressive. Are you gonna put that in your book?
真感人 你会把这个写到你的书里吗？
I gotta grab this. I'll meet you at the car rental.
我得接个电话 我去汽车租赁那儿找你
Hey, I was hoping I'd hear from you.
嘿，我还以为你会打给我
I'm in Hotlanta and I need a rib-joint recommend bad.
我在Hotlanta 能给我推荐个排骨店吗
Fat Matt's. Bring a bib.
胖Matt家，系上围裙
You never called. - I wasn't sure what was appropriate.
- 你没联系过我啊 - 我不知道合不合适
Appropriate? I'm not some waitress you banged in a snowstorm.
合适？我可不是什么在暴风雪的时候 碰见的女服务员
That word has no place in our vocabulary.
我们的字典里可没那个词
I'm the woman that you don't have to worry about.
我是那种你不用担心的女人
Sounds like a trap. - Listen...
- 听起来像个陷阱 - 听着
the next time that you're worried about manners, don't.
下次考虑什么礼貌的时候 就省了吧
If you wanna call, call. Just think of me as yourself, only with a vagina.
如果想打电话，就打 把我当你自己，只不过多了个阴道
When am I gonna see you?
我什么时候能见到你？
Well, I'm out of Hartsfield into IAD, with a connection in ORD into SDF.
我要从哈茨菲尔德飞到华盛顿 然后在芝加哥转机去路伊维尔
Sorry.
真可惜
Yeah, tell me about it.
怎么了
How long's your layover? They got multiples into SDF. Could you push?
你转机有多长时间？鲁伊维尔有很多航班 你能推一推吗
Yeah, I can push.
行，我可以推
All you have to do today is watch and listen.
今天你要做的就是观看和聆听
And when I talk about a strategy packet, hand them one of those.
当我说到策略书的时候 你递给他们
Sounds great.
好的
So although I wish I were here with better news,
尽管我也希望我带来的是好消息
the fact is that you and I are sitting here today because
实际上今天我们坐在这儿
this will be your last week of employment at this company.
因为这是你在这个公司的最后一周
Why me? - What am I supposed to do now?
- 为什么是我？ - 我现在该怎么办？
Am I supposed to feel better I'm not the only one losing my job?
我是不是应该庆幸 我不是唯一失业的人？
This is ridiculous! I have been a fine employee for over 10 years
这太荒谬了！ 我是10年的优秀员工
and this is the way you treat me.
这就是你们给我的回报
How do you sleep at night, man? How?
你晚上能睡得好吗？
How's your family? They sleeping well at night?
你的家人呢，他们睡得好吗？
Electricity still on?
供电正常？
Heat still on, refrigerator full of food?
暖气热着，冰箱里都是食物？
Gas tank full of gas?
油箱里有汽油？
Going to Chuck E. Cheese this weekend or something?
周末要去Chuck E奶酪什么的？
Not me.
我没有
No, my kids, we're not gonna do anything.
不，我的孩子 我们什么也做不了
What do you suggest I tell them?
你让我怎么跟他们说？
Perhaps you're underestimating the positive effect
也许您低估了职业过渡
your career transition can have on your children.
给您孩子带来的积极影响
The positive effect?
积极影响？
I make about 90 grand a year now.
我现在一年赚9万
Unemployment is what - 250 bucks a week?
失业后回怎样，每周250？
Is that one of your positive effects?
这就是你所说的积极效果？
We'll get to be cosier cos I'm not gonna be able to pay my mortgage on my house.
我们会变得更舒服 因为我付不起房子的贷款？
So maybe we can move into a nice fucking one-bedroom apartment somewhere.
也许我们会搬到什么破单间
And I guess without benefits,
而且没有救济金
I'll be able to hold my daughter as she, you know, suffers from her asthma
当我女儿哮喘发作而受罪时
that I won't be able to afford the medication for.
我只能抱着她，而支付不起医疗费
Well...tests have shown that children under moderate trauma have a tendency to
实验证明中度哮喘的孩子
apply themselves academically...
学习会更加努力
..as a method of coping.
以此作为一种应对方法
Go fuck yourself.
去死吧你
That's what my kids'll think.
我孩子将来会这么想
Your children's admiration is important to you? - Yeah.
- 你孩子的敬佩对你来说很重要？ - 是的
Yeah, it was.
曾经是
Well, I doubt they ever admired you, Bob.
我怀疑他们是否敬佩过你，Bob
Hey, asshole, aren't you supposed to be consoling me?
嘿，你个混球 你是不是应该安慰我？
I'm not a shrink, Bob. I'm a wake-up call.
我不是个出气筒，Bob 我是来提醒你的
You know why kids love athletes? - Cos they screw lingerie models?
- 你知道孩子们为什么喜欢运动员？ - 因为他们和内衣模特乱搞？
No, that's why we love athletes. Kids love athletes
不，那是我们 孩子们喜欢运动员
because they follow their dreams.
因为他们可以追随他们的梦想
Well, I can't dunk. - No, but you can cook.
- 我可扣不了篮 - 可你会烹饪
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢？
Your résum?says that you minored in French culinary arts.
你的简历显示你辅修过 法国烹饪艺术
Most students, they work on the fryer at KFC,
大多数的学生 在KFC的油锅上炸薯条
but you bussed tables at Il Picador to support yourself.
可你在Picador餐厅打工 已经养活了你自己
Then you get out of college and then you come and work here.
然后你毕业，来这儿工作
How much did they first pay you to give up on your dreams?
他们最初给你多少薪水 让你放弃了你的梦想？
27 grand a year. - And when were you going to stop
- 每年2万7 - 可你准备什么时候停下来
and come back and do what makes you happy?
回头去做让你快乐的事儿呢？
Good question.
问得好
I see guys who work at the same company for their entire lives,
我见过在一家公司干一辈子的人
guys exactly like you.
特别像你
They clock in, they clock out, and they never have a moment of happiness.
他们按点来，按点走 却从来没有一刻的幸福
You have an opportunity here, Bob.
你有这个机会，Bob
This is a rebirth.
去重生
If not for you, do it for your children.
不为你，也为了你的孩子们
He just waltzes in and cuts in line?
他就这么大摇大摆插队？
We reserve priority assistance for our Hilton Honors members.
我们对Hilton荣誉会员有优先服务
The promotions are great. You should check it out.
促销挺好的，你可以看看
Hungry much?
很饿吗？
Our business expense allots $40 each for dinner.
我们的差费指定40元的晚饭
I plan on grabbing as many miles as I can.
我计划积累尽量多的里程数
OK, you gotta fill me in on the miles thing. What is that about?
你得告诉我里程的事 到底怎么回事儿
Are you talking about... like frequent flyer miles?
你是说...常飞客户的里程？
You really want to know? - I'm dying to know.
- 真想知道 - 很想知道
I don't spend a nickel if I can help it unless it somehow profits my mileage account.
如果可以，我不会乱花一分钱 除非对我的里程帐户积累有益
So what are you saving up for - Hawaii, South of France?
你攒这么多干什么，去夏威夷？ 还是法国南部？
It's not like that. The miles are the goal.
不是，里程数就是目标
That's it?
仅仅如此？
You're saving just to save?
你就是为了攒而攒？
Just say I have a number in mind and I haven't hit it yet.
只能说我有一个目标，但还没达到
That's a little abstract. What's the target?
有点儿抽象，目标是多少？
I'd rather not. - Is it a secret target?
- 我宁愿没有 - 是个秘密的目标？
It's 10 million miles.
是1千万公里
OK. Isn't 10 million just a number? - Pi's just a number.
- 好吧，可1千万不就是个数字吗？ - 圆周率也只是个数字
Well, we all need a hobby.
我们都需要有个爱好
No, I... I don't mean to belittle your collection. I get it. It sounds cool.
不，我不是想鄙视你的努力 我明白了，听起来很酷
I'd be the seventh person to do it. More people have walked on the moon.
我将是第七个达到这个目标 登上月球的人都比这个多
Do they throw you a parade? - You get lifetime executive status,
- 他们会为你举行游行吗？ - 你将得到终生至尊会员身份
you get to meet the chief pilot, Maynard Finch...
你将会见到首席飞行员 Maynard Finch
And they put your name on a plane.
他们会把你的名字印在飞机上
Men get hard-ons putting their name on stuff. You guy;s dont grow up.
男人们总向往将名字印在什么东西上 你们就是长不大
It's like you need to pee on everything. - Now who's stereotyping?
- 就好像走到哪儿就在哪儿撒尿 - 到底谁是老古董啊？
Fear of mortality. It's like, yeah, you're gonna die one day.
对死亡的恐惧，就好像 对，你总会死的
Why is that singular to men?
为什么只针对男人？
Probably because you can't have babies. - The baby argument.
- 也许是因为你们不能生孩子 - 孩子论
If I had that many miles...
我要是有那么多里程...
I would show up at an airport,
我会去机场
look at the destination board, pick a place and go.
看看目的地的牌子 选一个地方，出发
Can't fall asleep.
睡不着
Me too just laying here
我也是，无聊躺着呢
You should rub one out.
你应该用手解决一下
Thank you for the advice.
谢谢你的建议
Only fair if you do too
你也做才公平
Way ahead of you.
早做过了
Call me next tim so I can listen
下次做的时候打电话给我 我可以听听
Have sweet dreams about me.
做个好梦，想着我
OK. Closer. Way closer.
好了，近一点，再近一点
Still closer.
再近一点
Closer.
近一点
Er...a little left.
向左点儿
Down a little.
往下点儿
Too far. Up. Up one more inch.
太远了，向上，向上一英寸
I don't get it. Why does your sister want a fake photo?
我搞不懂，为什么你妹妹要假照片？
My sister is kooky. She thinks this is charming. It's like the gnome thing.
我妹妹比较怪，她觉得这很有意思 就像童话一样
No, I mean, why would she want a fake photo in front of St Louis airport?
不是，我是说，为什么她要一个 St Louis机场的假照片？
Are you kidding - Lambert Field? The Wright brothers flew through there.
你开玩笑呢，Lambert区域？ 怀特兄弟飞过这儿
That domed main terminal,
那个穹顶候机楼
is the first of its kind, a precursor of everything from JFK to de Gaulle.
是世上第一座候机楼 是所有JFK机场，戴高乐机场们的先驱
Pretty sweet. - Just take the picture.
- 很感人 - 把照片拍了就行
Well, that's a keeper.
好了，照好了
Let me see it.
我看看
Why she wants reminders of all the places she hasn't been is beyond me.
我也不明白她为什么要这些 她没去过的照片
I'm sure she'll be crushed for having missed this airport.
我肯定要是没拍这个机场 她会崩溃的
Before Lindbergh crossed the Atlantic, he took off from that runway.
林德伯格跨越大西洋之前 他就是从那个跑道起飞的
Wonder why they called it the Spirit of St Louis?
想知道为什么他们叫它 圣路易斯的灵魂吗？
No. - Well...
- 不想 - 好吧...
Do you know how fucked this place is now?
你知道这个地方有多烂吗
I am the one thing - the one thing-
我才是唯一那个，唯一那个
preventing this place from being totally fucked in the ass.
可以阻止这个地方倒闭的人
Sometimes they just need to vent.
有时他们只是需要发泄一下
Please, for the love of God, can I fire the next one?
求求你，让我来解雇下一个？
Miss Barnes, thank you for joining us. - I'm here to be fired, right?
- Barnes小姐，谢谢您能来 - 我要被解雇了，是吗？
Well, we're here to talk about your future.
我们来这儿讨论你的未来
You don't have to sugar-coat it. I get the drill.
你不用再花言巧语了 我很清楚
What are they offering?
他们提供了什么？
Inside the packet, you'll find a clearly worked out severance package.
在这份材料里，你会发现一份 被辞人员的推荐方案
Give me the bullet points.
告诉我重点
It's actually pretty good -
事实上还不错
three months' pay, six months' medical.
3个月的薪水，6个月的医疗保险
And a full year of placement services through our CTC.
还有一年CTC提供的就业指导服务
Placement services. That's generous.
就业指导服务，很慷慨啊
Commonly it takes a month of searching for every $10,000 you expect to earn in salary.
通常找一份年薪1万元的工作 要花一个月时间
So I could be looking for a while. - Not necessarily.
- 这么说我得找一阵儿了 - 也不一定
Don't even sweat it. I'm pretty confident about my plans.
别费力气了，我对自己的计划很有信心
Really? - Yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是的
There's this beautiful bridge by my house.
我房子旁边有座漂亮的桥
I'm gonna go jump off it.
我会跳下去
Natalie.
Natalie
Hey!
嘿！
Natalie!
Natalie!
People say these things all the time. It's part of the trade.
人们总是会说这样的话 这是讨价还价的一部分
They do? - Yeah.
- 是吗 - 是的
They say crazy things. They get worked up.
他们会说些疯话，非常激动
She was really calm.
她刚才很平静
I think that's a good sign.
我想这是个好的信号
So they don't ever actually do it? - No. No, it's just talk.
- 他们不会真那么做？ - 不会，不会，他们只是说说
How do you know? Do you follow up? - No, nothing good's gonna come of that, but..
- 你怎么知道？你跟过他们？ - 没有，跟着他们没什么好下场,可…
I wouldn't worry about it.
我不会担心
This is what we do, Natalie. We take people at their most fragile and we set them adrift.
这就是我们的工作，Natlie 我们在人们最脆弱的时候拉他们一把 然后又放其随波逐流
Ready to go back in?
准备好回去了吗？
All right, let's go. Come on.
好了，我们走吧
No, I'm fine. Tell me something sweet.
没，我挺好的，说点儿高兴的
I'll be back soon. I'm not sure how long this exercise is supposed to last.
我就回去了，我也不确定 这个实习要持续多久
No, I don't even think of him that way. He's old.
没有，我连看都不看他一眼 他太老了
I- I'm done? - I wasn't expecting this. Not at all.
- 我完蛋了？ - 我没想到会这样，完全没想到
Just like that?
就这样？
I'm disappointed that I've given so much of my life...
我很失望，投入了这么多...
This is not fair.
这不公平
There are people way more qualified than me now.
现在有人比我更有资格了
I don't know what to do when I wake up tomorrow.
我不知道明早起来干什么
You OK?
你还好吧？
Are we going? - Yeah.
- 走了吗？ - 走吧
This is how I start every day of my life.
我就是这样开始我每天的生活
Now, this is gonna be a little difficult, so stay with me.
这么和我在一起会有点儿辛苦
You have a new backpack.
你有一个新的背包
Only this time, I want you to fill it with people.
这次，我想让你们往里面装人
Start with casual acquaintances, friends of friends,
从你们的熟人开始，朋友的朋友
folks around the office.
办公室的同僚
And then the people you trust with your most intimate secrets -
然后你最信任的人
your cousins, your aunts, your uncles,
你的堂兄，姑姑，叔叔
your brothers, your sisters, your parents,
你的兄弟姐妹，你的父母
and finally your husband, your wife, your boyfriend or your girlfriend.
最后是你的丈夫，妻子 男朋友或者女朋友
You get them into that backpack.
你把他们装进这个背包
Don't worry. I'm not gonna ask you to light it on fire.
别担心，我不会让你们烧它的
Feel the weight of that bag.
感觉到背包的重量了吗
Make no mistake, your relationships are the heaviest components in your life.
没错的话，你的人际关系是你生活 最重要的部分
Do you feel the straps cutting into your shoulders?
你感觉到背带嵌入你的肩膀？
All those negotiations and arguments, and secrets and compromises.
所有那些谈判，争论，秘密，妥协啊
You don't need to carry all that weight.
你不必搬着那么多重量
Why don't you set that bag down?
为什么不把背包放下？
Some animals were meant to carry each other, to live symbiotically for a lifetime -
有些动物总是背着彼此 共生一辈子
star-crossed lovers, monogamous swans. We are not those animals.
时运不济的恋人，一夫一妻的天鹅们 我们不是那些动物
The slower we move, the faster we die.
我们移动的越慢，我们死的越快
We are not swans.
我们不是天鹅
We're sharks.
我们是鲨鱼
Never? - No.
- 从不？ - 从不
Ever?
- 永远不？ - 永远不
You never want to get married? - Nope.
- 你从不想结婚？ - 不想
Never want kids? - Not a chance.
- 不想要孩子？ - 绝不
Ever? - Never.
- 永远不？ - 永远
Is that so bizarre? - Yes.
- 这很奇怪吗 - 是的
Yes, it is. - I just don't see the value in it.
- 是的，很奇怪 - 我只是看不到其中的价值
Right, sell it to me. - What?
- 好吧，说服我 - 什么？
Sell me marriage.
说服我结婚
OK, how about love? - OK.
- 好，那爱情呢 - 好吧
Stability, just somebody you can count on... - How many stable marriages do you know?
- 稳定，有个可以依靠的人 - 你见过多少稳定的婚姻
Somebody to talk to, someone to spend your life with.
有人说话，可以和你过一辈子的人
I'm surrounded by people to talk to. That won't change.
我周围都是人，这不会改变
How about just not dying alone?
不用孤独的死去呢？
Starting when I was 12, we moved each of my grandparents to a nursing facility.
从我12岁开始，我们将爷爷奶奶 送到看护机构
My parents went the same way. Make no mistake, we all die alone.
我父母也是 没错的话，我们都会孤独死去
Now, those cult members in San Diego, with the Kool-Aid and the sneakers...
只有那些San Diego的信徒们 喝着Kool-Aid饮料，穿着运动鞋
they didn't die alone.
他们不会孤独的死去 （1997年，加州圣地亚哥市：天堂之门： 39名信徒集体自杀，因服用过量药物或窒息而死）
I'm just saying there are options.
我只是想说这是人们的选择
Oh, fuck.
哦，靠
Brian left me.
Brian甩了我
All right.
没事儿
OK. Ok. All right.
好了，好了，没事儿
All right. Shh, shh.
没事儿，嘘，嘘
Natalie, this is Alex, my friend. This is Natalie.
Natalie，这是Alex，我朋友 这是Natalie
I should give you both a moment.
我应该给你们点儿时间
No. No, that's fine. I'm fine. It's a pleasure to meet you.
不，不，没事儿 我挺好的，很高兴见到你
Maybe we should just all go up to our rooms and freshen up.
我们还去房间洗洗吧
Maybe a drink? - Now you're talking.
- 喝点儿酒？ - 好的
Brian: I think it's time we C othter people
Brian：我觉得我们分手吧
He broke up with you with a text message?
他发短信和你分手？
Kind of like firing someone over the internet.
有点儿像远程解雇员工
What a weaselly prick. - But what does that make me?
- 真是个狡猾的混蛋 - 我成了什么？
Someone who falls for a prick. - We all fall for them.
- 爱上了混蛋的人 - 我们都会喜欢这种人
Pricks are spontaneous, unpredictable and fun.
混蛋们总是很自然，不可预期 还挺有意思
Then we're surprised when they turn out to be pricks.
当他们露出真面目时 我们才会大吃一惊
I followed him to Omaha. - You did?
- 我跟他到了奥马哈 - 是吗？
I had a job waiting for me in San Francisco when he got an offer from ConAgra.
我在旧金山有个工作机会 可他被ConAgra食品集团录用了
He said we could start a life together.
他说我们可以一起生活
So I followed him. - To Nebraska?
- 于是我就跟着他 - 到了Nebraska
I thought I'd be engaged by now.
我以为我现在都订婚了
No offence.
无意冒犯
None taken. - That's all right.
- 没事儿 - 没关系
When I was 16, I thought by 23 I'd be married,
我16岁的时候 我以为23岁就会结婚
maybe have a kid, corner office by day, entertaining at night.
生个孩子，白天去办公室 晚上去娱乐
I was supposed to be driving a Grand Cherokee by now.
我本应该开辆大切诺基的
Life can underwhelm you that way.
那样的生活会让你觉得了无生趣
I mean, where did you think you'd be by um...
你们觉得你们会到哪儿
It doesn't work that way. - At a certain point, you stop with the deadlines.
- 我们不是那么想的 - 在最终期限前停了下来
It can be counterproductive.
那样可能达不到目标的
I don't want to say anything anti-feminist.
我不想说反对女权主义的话
I really appreciate all your generation did for me.
我很感激你们这一代人所做的
It was our pleasure. - Well done.
- 没什么 - 说得好
But sometimes it feels like, no matter how much success I have,
可有时候，就好像不管我多成功
it's not gonna matter until I find the right guy.
都无所谓，直到我找到真命天子
You really thought this guy was the one?
你真的以为这个家伙就是？
I could have made it work.
我本可以让它实现
He um... He really fit the bill.
他，呃，很对胃口
You know? - The bill?
- 明白吗？ - 对胃口？
White collar, college grad.
白领，大学毕业
Loves dogs, likes funny movies. Six-foot-one, brown hair, kind eyes,
喜欢狗，喜欢喜剧电影 6尺1寸高，棕色头发，温柔的眼睛
works in finance but is outdoorsy... you know, on the weekends.
在金融系统工作 但周末喜欢户外活动
I always imagined he'd have a single syllable name like Matt or John...
我一直想象他还有个单音节名字 比如Matt或者John
or Dave.
或者Dave
In a perfect world, he drives a 4Runner, and
最好的话，他开一辆四驱的车
and the only thing he loves more than me is his golden lab.
唯一喜欢胜于我的是他的金毛狗
And a nice smile.
还要有迷人的微笑
What about you? - Let me think.
- 你呢？ - 让我想想
Honestly, by the time you're 34, all the physical requirements go out the window.
坦白说，在你34岁的时候 所有的物质需求已经不重要
Like you secretly pray that he'll be taller than you.
就像你私下里希望他比你高
Not an asshole would be nice. Someone who enjoys my company, comes from a good family.
只要不是个混蛋，喜欢我的公司 出身比较好
You don't think about that when you're younger.
你年轻时候不会考虑这些的
I don't know... someone who wants kids.
我不确定...他想要孩子
Likes kids. Wants kids
喜欢孩子，想要孩子
Healthy enough to play with his kids.
身体健康，能和孩子们玩
Please let him earn more money than I do.
让他挣得比我多
You might not understand that now, but believe me, you will one day.
你可能现在还不理解 相信我，总有一天你会的
Otherwise that's a recipe for disaster.
否则就是个灾难
And hopefully some hair on his head.
最好不要是个秃子
But I mean even that's not a deal breaker these days.
不过我想现在来讲 那也不是决定性条件
A nice smile.
一个迷人的微笑
Yeah, a nice smile. Nice smile just might do it.
对，迷人的微笑 迷人的微笑也许就够了
Wow, that was depressing.
哇，真让人心情压抑
I should just date women. - Tried it.
- 我也许应该和女人约会 - 试试吧
We're no picnic ourselves.
女人自己都很麻烦
I don't mind being married to my career.
我不介意和我的工作结婚
And I don't expect it to hold me in bed as I fall asleep.
我也不期望它能抱着我睡觉
I just don't want to settle.
我只是不想安顿下来
You're young. Right now you see settling as some sort of a failure.
你还年轻，现在你觉得安定就是 一种失败
It is...by definition.
理论上...确实是
But by the time someone is right for you, it won't feel like settling.
可当你的真命天子来了的时候 你就不会那么觉得了
And the only person left to judge you
唯一来评论你的人
will be the 23-year-old girl with a target on your back.
将是你背后某个有目标的23岁女孩
So what's the plan for the evening?
今晚有什么计划吗？
Well, we were gonna hit that party for the tech conference at the hotel.
我们要参加酒店里一个 技术会议的派对
I didn't know you could just attend those. I thought you had to register.
我不知道那些可以直接参加 我还以为要注册
Technically, I don't think it's open to the public.
严格来说，是不对公众开放
Stop by. - You're gonna crash it?
- 只是路过 - 你们要混进去？
have a good time, usually. - No, no, I get it. I'm in.
- 去玩玩，通常 - 不，不，我明白，我也去
Jennifer Chu?
Jennifer Chu？
Shit! - Ah, it'll be fine.
- 该死！ - 没事儿
Doing all right?
你还好吗？
Yeah. This was a great idea.
很好，这主意太棒了
You're so pretty.
你太漂亮了
You're exactly what I wanna look like in 15 years.
你就是我15年后想变成的样子
Thank you, Natalie. - You should dance.
- 谢谢，Natalie - 你们应该去跳舞
Come on. - No, no, no.
- 来吧 - 不，不，不
- Oh!
- 哦！
I'm Dave. - I'm Natalie.
- 我叫Dave - 我叫Natalie
Who's Jennifer?
Jennifer是谁？
I don't know.
我不知道
How's everybody doing out there?
大家玩得怎么样？
Right about now, give it up for a very special alphaTECH guest.
现在停一下，欢迎alphaTECH的特别嘉宾
Young MC!
Young MC！
What's up, alphaTECH?
玩得好吗，alphaTECH？
I got a busted computer. Can somebody fix it for me?
我电脑坏了 谁能帮我修好？
I want you to have a key to my place.
我把住地的门卡给你
Wow. I had no idea we were at that point in our relationship.
哇，我都不知道我们已经发展到这种关系了
Oh,yes. - Wow.
- 哦，是的 - 哇
Where is she?
她在哪？
Back home I don't get to act the way I do with you.
回到家我就不能像现在这样了
That's why I don't have a back home. - I know.
- 这就是我不要家的原因 - 我知道
You're so cool. Mr Empty Backpack.
你太酷了，空背包先生
You know about my backpack? - I Googled you.
- 你知道我的背包理论？ - 我google过你
You did?
是吗？
It's what us modern girls do when we have a crush.
现在的女生遇到男人时都是这样
Does it bother you? - It depends.
- 让你困扰了吗？ - 不一定
Is the bag empty because you hate people or because you hate the baggage they come along with?
不带包袱是因为你讨厌交际 还是因为你讨厌交际所带来的负担？
I don't hate people. I'm not exactly a hermit.
我不讨厌交际，我又不是隐士
You just don't want to be tied down with the whole responsibility thing.
你只是不想被责任束缚？
I don't know what originally sparked the backpack.
开始的原因我也不记得了
Probably needed to be alone.
可能是想要独身一人吧
Recently,I've been thinking that I needed to empty the backpack
最近我一直在想，需要清空背包
before I know what to put back in it.
这样才能把别的东西放进去
Oh,no! - I think we're out of gas.
- 哦，不是吧 - 估计船没油了
Hey. You're up?
嘿，你起床了？
I have to fly standby and make a meeting in Cincinnati.
我要飞到辛辛那提开个会
I made you feel cheap.
我让你吃亏了啊
It's all right. Just leave the money on the dresser.
没事，把钱留在梳妆台上就行了
I'll text you later so we can swap schedules.
待会我会给你短信 以便我们交换行程
I really like you.
我真的很喜欢你
I like you too. - Good.
- 我也喜欢你 - 那就好
Go catch your plane.
去赶飞机吧
Last night er...
昨晚，呃…
It was kind of out of hand. I said things erm...
有点失控，我说过的，呃…
I'm not actually sure everything that I said.
我记不太清了
But I didn't want you to think... - Just relax.
- 但我不想让你觉得… - 放轻松
It was nice to see you cut loose.
看到你能轻松了真不错
Did you wake him up or slip out?
你把他叫醒了还是自己溜出来了？
What? - This morning. Your new friend.
- 什么？ - 今早，你的新朋友
Did you wake him up for an awkward goodbye,or did you
你是叫醒他然后尴尬的道别
just slip out and make him feel like a whore?
还是悄悄溜了出来，让他觉得你是个婊子
I just left. - Protocol's always tricky.
- 我溜出来的 - 都是这样的
What happened to Alex?
Alex怎样了？
She had to leave town early to get to a meeting.
她要去开会早先就走了
That's too bad. Where's she live? - Chicago.
- 真是的，她住在哪？ - 芝加哥
Thinking of going to see her?
想去看她吗？
We don't really have that kind of relationship. Try it over there.
我们没到那种关系 在那边试试
What erm... kind of relationship do you have?
那你们是什么关系？
Well,you know...casual.
你知道…很随意
Sounds pretty special. - It works for us.
- 听起来很特别 - 对我们来说不错
Don't you think there's a future there?
没想过你们的未来吗？
I never thought about it. What's going on?
从没有想过，问这个干吗？
Really never thought about it? - No.
- 真的从没想过？ - 是的
How can you not think about that?
你怎么能这样？
How does it not cross your mind you might want a future with someone?
你怎么就不会想想 有某个人和你在一起的未来？
It's simple. You know that moment when you look into somebody's eyes
很简单，当你和恋人相互注视
and you can feel them staring into your soul and the whole world goes quiet just for a second?
你能感觉到时间的静止和心灵的交会吗？
Yes. - Right. Well,I don't.
- 是的 - 对，但我不会
You're an asshole.
你这个混蛋
I'm just dicking around. Give me a hand. - Shouldn't you give her a chance?
- 我玩玩而已嘛，来帮帮我 - 你不应该给她机会吗？
A chance for what? - A chance at something real.
- 什么机会？ - 真正在一起的机会
Natalie,your definition of real will evolve as you get older.
Natalie，你对真正在一起的理解会随着年龄增长而改变的
Can you stop condescending for one second or is it a principle of your bullshit philosophy?
你就不能屈服一次 还是这就是你的狗屁哲学？
Bullshit philosophy? - The isolation,the travelling.
- 狗屁哲学？ - 独自一人，旅行
Is that supposed to be charming? - No,it's a life choice.
- 那很棒吗？ - 这是我选择的生活方式
It's a cocoon of self-banishment. - Wow. Big words.
- 你就等着吃苦果吧 - 开始教导我了
Screw you. - Screw you,too.
- 去你的
You have set up a way of life that makes it impossible for you to have any human connection.
你选择了基本不和任何人交际的生活方式
And this woman comes along and runs the gauntlet of your life choice,
而这个女人不畏艰难地来到了你身边
and comes out on the other end smiling just so you can call her "casual"?
你却用“随意”来敷衍？
I need to grow up? You're a 12-year-old.
我还没长大？ 你才是个小孩
I don't have a gauntlet...
我又没那么难相处…
Fuck.
操
Listen,these Detroit guys can be tough. They're getting hammered.
听着，底特律的这帮人不好惹 他们遭受了重创
Don't get distracted. Stick with the simple stuff.
不要分心，把基本的事做好
Get these packets in their hands and get them out the door,OK?
把册子给他们，然后送他们出门，明白吗？
Hey,welcome to Detroit.
嘿，欢迎来到底特律
What's going on here?
这是在搞什么？
I've been looking at those great numbers. I thought we should nut up and give this a try.
我最近在关注公司业绩，看来我们该来试试这个了
We could use a little more time.
我们还需要点时间
You gotta leave the nest at some point,huh?
总得开个头，是吧？
This a real company,Craig. We're here to do some damage.
这是个真正的公司，Craig 我们又不是来做善事
I know. It's a good thing we brought our best. Let's stop screwing around.
我知道，所以才亮出王牌 别磨蹭了
Just give me a minute to prepare and get my things together.
给我点时间准备准备
I thought Natalie was going to take this one.
这次让Natalie来吧
She's hardly ready for that.
她还没准备好
I've watched her results the last few days. She's great.
我刚看过她的成果，非常棒
This is a whole other animal.
这次的对象完全不一样
You know,she created it,right? Natalie,are you not up for it?
这可是她的点子，对吧？ Natalie，准备好了没？
Yeah,I'm game.
没问题
That's my girl.
这就对了
Just remember,don't apologise or tell them how hard this is for you.
记住，不要道歉或者表现出同情
Today's one of the worst days they're ever gonna have. How we feel doesn't even compare.
今天是他们经历过的最糟糕的一天 我们的同情不值一提
Got it. - Keep it professional. You'll be fine.
- 明白 - 要专业，没事的
What's all this? What's going on?
这是什么玩意？怎么回事？
Hello,Mr Samuels.
Samuels先生，您好
I wish I were here with better news.
我也希望带给您好消息
However,your position here is no longer available.
可是，您已经被解雇了
What are you talking about?
你说什么？
You've been let go.
公司把您解雇了
Just like that?
就这样？
Who are you?
你是谁？
My name is Miss Keener and I'm here today to talk about your options.
我是Keener女士，今天是来讨论您的选择
I worked for this company for 17 years and they send a 4th-grader to can me?
我在这家公司干了17年 他们就派个菜鸟来炒我？
What the fuck is this?
这他妈的什么道理？
It's perfectly normal to be upset.
可以理解您的愤怒
However,the sooner you can tell yourself greater opportunities...
然而，您越早的接受现实 就会有越大的机会等着您
Greater opportunities? I'm 57 fucking years old.
更大的机会？我他妈57岁了
Anybody who ever built an empire or changed the world sat where you are now.
很多曾经建立帝国或者改变世界的人 都有过与您现在相似的处境
And it's because they sat there that they were able to do it.
而正因为他们经历过这个 才会有能力完成那些事业
There's a packet in front of you. I want you to take some time and review it.
您面前有一本小册子，希望您能花点时间看看
All the answers you're looking for are inside those pages.
里面能解答您所有的疑惑
The sooner you trust the process,the sooner the next step of your life will unveil itself.
越早接受现实 未来的面纱才能越快的揭开
I need you to go back to your office and put together your personal things.
现在请您回办公室收拾个人物品
Mr Samuels, that's all we can discuss now.
Samuels先生，我们到此为止了
Mr Samuels.
Samuels先生
Mr Samuels!
Samuels先生！
You did good.
干得好
You OK? You want me to take over?
你还好吗？用不用我来？
No,I'm all right.
不用，我很好
Look,we just got here. That's one place. We need to try a few more.
我们才刚到第一个地方 应该多试试
Maybe it makes no difference,but it's comforting to know we're in the next room.
可能没多大区别 但是如果我们知道就在隔壁会感觉更好
I know you don't give a shit about my comfort.
我知道你不把我的安慰当回事
I think we could try a few more, that's all I'm saying.
我要说的就是，我们应该多试试
Fine.
好吧
All right. OK. All right.
好吧，就这样
He thought you did a great job. You did.
他觉得你干得很棒，你确实很棒
I'm real proud of you. - Thanks.
- 我为你骄傲 - 谢谢
They're pulling us off the road.
他们让我们回去
We're going home.
我们要回家了
Really? For good - Yeah.
- 真的吗，永远不回来了？ - 是的
Good job.
干得好
We request the pleasure of your company at the wedding of Julie Bingham and James Arthur Miller
诚挚地邀请您出席Julie Bingham和James Arthur Miller的婚礼
I'm sorry about what I said about Alex. That was out of line.
我很抱歉说过的关于Alex的话，那太过分了
It's all right. I understand.
没关系，我能理解
I mean,who am I to be doling out relationship advice,right?
我还不够格给别人情感建议，是吧？
No kidding.
别开玩笑了
Are you gonna be OK?
你还好吧？
What do you mean? - In Omaha?
- 什么意思？ - 只能待在奥马哈？
I don't know.
我也不知道
It's better than you'd think.
会比你想象的更好的
Ryan.
Ryan
Ryan. Where are you going? - I'm grabbing another flight.
- Ryan，你要去哪？ - 我去乘另一个航班
Something I've got to take care of. I'll see you back at home.
得去处理点事情，回去见
OK,walk it in a little.
过来一点点
A little more.
再来一点
There you go. Yeah.
好了
Got it.
搞定
They're a cute couple.
他们真可爱
You think so? - Yeah,they'll make cute kids.
- 你这么认为？ - 是啊，他们的孩子一定也很可爱
How do you like Wisconsin in February?
你觉得二月的威斯康辛怎么样？
I like it if you're there. I know a killer burger in Milwaukee.
你在的话我会喜欢 我知道密尔沃基有一家很棒的汉堡店
Northern Wisconsin.
北威斯康辛
What are you doing this weekend?
你这周末怎么安排的？
No. - What,I haven't...
- 不 - 我还没...
You want me to be your date? - Yeah. Yeah.
- 你想让我当你的女伴？ - 是啊，是啊
At your sister's wedding? - It's not like I know her that well.
- 出席你妹妹的婚礼？ - 我和她又不怎么熟
Look,I'm not the wedding type,right?
我不是喜欢婚礼的那种人，对吧？
But for the first time in my life I don't want to be that guy alone at a bar.
但头一回我不想在酒吧独自一人
I want a dance partner, I want a "plus one".
我想有个舞伴，想要有人陪伴
And if you can stomach it, I'd like it to be you.
如果你不介意，我希望那就是你
Excuse me. Are you available?
打扰了，您可以办理吗？
This line's for members of our Matterhorn Programme.
这里是专门为Matterhorn会员准备的
Hey...Ryan.
嘿，Ryan
Hey. - Kara. Hi.
- 嘿 - Kara，你好啊
Alex,this is my sister Kara. - Hi.
- Alex，这是我姐姐，Kara - 你好
Well,hello.
你好
Ryan's told me nothing about you.
Ryan从没和我说起过你
So you two are dating?
你们俩在约会吗？
Not exactly. - Well,don't worry about it.
- 不算吧 - 不用担心
We're all getting a little old to be calling someone girlfriend.
我们已经过了谈恋爱的年龄了
I remember when Mom used to call Jack her boyfriend.
我记得有一次妈妈叫Jack“男朋友”
Drove me up the wall. Boyfriends are for kids,right?
肉麻死了 男朋友什么的都是小孩子才叫的，对吧？
So what are you doing at the hotel?
你在这干什么呢？
Yeah,OK,er...Frank and I are trying out a trial separation.
呃...我和Frank正试着分居
I'm sorry. So you're not at the house? - No,there was a room on hold here,
- 抱歉，你不住家里了？ - 不了，这边有个房间
so I thought I'd take it for the weekend.
我周末过来住
So the rehearsal dinner? - Yeah,tonight. I'll see you there.
- 婚宴排练是什么时候？ - 今晚，到时见
Nice digs.
房间不错
There's a packet.
这有本册子
Hey,look who's here.
看看谁来了
Oh,my God! Oh,my God! Ryan! - Hey.
- 天哪，Ryan！ - 嘿
Oh,you must be Alex. - Yes,I am. Hi. How are you?
- 你一定是Alex - 是的，你好
You are so beautiful. Kara was right.
你真漂亮，Kara说的对
Gosh. You look so grown-up.
天哪，你看起来成熟多了
I do? You're the one that's getting married.
是吗？你才是要结婚的啊
Oh,I know,right?
哦，可不是吗？
Oh. You haven't even seen my ring.
你还没看我的戒指呢
Oh,look at that. - Oh,it's lovely.
- 哦，你瞧瞧 - 真不错
Jim designed it.
Jim设计的
Hey,Jim.
嘿，Jim
Hey. - How's it going?
- 嘿 - 你们好啊
Hey. I'm Ryan. - Jim. Good to meet you.
- 嘿，我是Ryan - 我是Jim，很高兴见到你
Alex. Pleasure. - Pleasure.
- 我是Alex，很荣幸 - 很荣幸
Thank you,guys,for coming.
谢谢你们能来
Brother!
老哥！
It's true,though. - Yeah,it's crazy.
- 倒是真的 - 是啊，真奇妙
I got the pictures you asked me to get. - You can just put them right there.
- 我带来你们要的照片了 - 放在那边吧
Yeah,OK.
好的
You got so many up there, I almost didn't have room.
有那么多照片，我差点没地方放
I know. It's so great,everyone just chipped in.
是啊，真是感动，大家都帮了忙
What gave you the idea to do something so...
你怎么会想到去做这么…
Substantial. - Well...
- 充实的事情 - 这个嘛…
Jim has a lot of our nest egg invested in this real estate venture.
Jim把我们大部分的积蓄都投入房地产了
Mm-hm. It's a real estate investment.
嗯，一项房地产投资
It's exciting, but we went over our finances and...
很不错，但当我们查看积蓄...
A honeymoon at this state in the game doesn't really seem affordable.
蜜月旅行恐怕是负担不起了
So,you know,we just thought,
所以我们就想
just because we can't travel doesn't mean we can't have pictures.
不能旅行不意味着不能拍照留念
I think that's a fabulous idea. - Yeah,it's a good one.
- 这主意真棒 - 好想法
The concept is turnkey everything.
我们的理念是一条龙服务
You buy a maintenance contract when you get the home. We'll whack your weeds,
你买房时，我们帮你处理杂草
change your light bulbs. Furniture - you can bring your own or pick one of our packages.
换新的灯泡、家具，用你自己的或者选择我们的都可以
Seamless traditionalism,yet all the perks. - Nice.
- 传统的房子，全方位的享受 - 不错
We all need a place to call our own. This is America. This is what we were promised.
我们都需要自己的家 这就是美国，这就是我们的承诺
It's a nice touch. - What?
- 说得好 - 什么？
The bit at the end about the promise. I like that part.
最后关于承诺的，我很赞成
Oh,thanks.
谢谢
You er...you still renting that one-bedroom? - No. I gave it up.
- 你还租着那个单间？ - 没，退掉了
So you own now? - No.
- 那你买房了？ - 没
But you're looking?
但在找？
No,not really.
不算吧
So you're just good?
那你也过的不错？
I'm good. - Well,that's good.
- 很好 - 那就好
Can you believe it's tomorrow? How are you gonna sleep?
你能相信就是明天了吗？ 怎么能睡着啊？
I don't know.
我也不知道
Well,do you want some Xanax? - I don't think that's for sleeping.
- 要不要点赞安诺？ - 那不是治失眠的吧
Yeah. No,I think I'll just have a glass of warm milk.
不用了，我喝杯热牛奶就行了
That'll do the trick. - OK. See you tomorrow.
- 那会有效的 - 明天见
There's another box inside.
里面还有一箱
I'll grab it. - You sure?
- 我去拿吧？ - 没问题吧？
Yeah,yeah,yeah.
没事
Jim seems like a good guy. - Yeah,isn't he great?
- Jim看起来人不错 - 是啊，他很棒吧
He's going to make a great husband.
他会是个好丈夫的
You know,Julie,I was thinking, you know,with Dad not being here,erm...
Julie，我在想，爸爸不在这...
I was wondering if you had anybody to walk you down the aisle.
有没有人陪你走入婚礼殿堂？
No,Jim's uncle is gonna do it. - He's been really supportive.
- Jim的叔叔答应陪我了 - 他真的很积极
He's been great.
他人很好
Well,good. That's great. I just wanted to make sure that you...
呃，那太好了，我只是想知道你…
I wanted you to be covered,that's all.
有人陪着你
So,I should be there,what?
那我应该几点到？
The other guests are arriving around five and things get going at five-thirty so...
其他客人大约五点到 我们五点半开始…
around then. - OK.
- 就那时候吧 - 好吧
Oh. Let me... I'm gonna help you with those.
哦，我来帮你拿
Got it.
好了
It's OK. It's OK,it's OK.
没事，没事的
None of that was here.
这些以前都没有
This is all new.
全都是新建的
Really?
不会吧？
Is that all you got? - What?
- 你就这点本事？ - 什么？
Give me a boost.
推我一下
Watch...
当心
Hang on.
等下
I took Geography in here.
我在这上地理课
You ever fool around with one of your teachers?
有没有和老师乱搞？
No. Did you? - No. Not until college.
- 没有，你呢？ - 直到大学才有
That's me on the right.
右边那个是我
It's kinda hard to tell. - You can tell by the eyebrows.
- 都认不出来了 - 眉毛没变
You played basketball? - I was a point guard. Don't act so surprised.
- 你以前打篮球？ - 我是控卫，别这么吃惊嘛
I didn't know you were such a jock.
真不知道你还是个运动健将
That's me too.
那也是我
And that.
那个也是
My first fight. - How'd it go?
- 我第一次打架的地方 - 怎么样？
Got my ass kicked.
被人揍了一顿
This is where we used to go to make out. - Oh,yes. Yeah. This is very romantic.
- 这就是以前我们亲热的地方 - 是啊，这很浪漫
I'm really happy I came here. - So am I.
- 我真的很开心能到这来 - 我也是
It's Kara.
是Kara
Ryan,where are you? We're having a meltdown here.
Ryan，你在哪？ 出事了
What's going on? What happened?
怎么了，发生什么了？
It's Jim. Can you get back here? We need your help.
是Jim的事，你能回来吗？ 我们需要你帮忙
OK.
好的
We gotta go.
我们要走了
I'll grab your suit. - Thanks.
- 我帮你拿西装 - 谢谢
What happened? - Jim's got cold feet.
- 怎么了？ - Jim怯场了
Today? - Yeah,that's how cold feet work.
- 今天？ - 当然是今天
What do you want me to do? - Talk to him.
- 你想让我做什么？ - 和他谈谈
You want me to talk to him? - Hey,it's either you or me.
- 你让我和他谈谈？ - 不是你就是我
You know my track record. I've already struck out once.
你又不是不知道，我已经搞砸一次了
I haven't been to bat. I haven't been in the dugout.
我没有类似经验
Don't you talk for a living? Motivational-type stuff?
你不是靠谈话赚钱吗？励志式的讲话？
I tell people how to avoid commitment.
- 我教的是让别人如何逃避责任 - 这是什么他妈的玩意
It's a philosophy. - It's stupid.
- 这是生活哲学 - 这太愚蠢了
Hey,it could have helped you. - Ryan.
- 但可以帮到你 - Ryan
You haven't been around much. Fuck - basically,you don't exist to us.
你不怎么在我们身边 操，实话说，你对我们来说根本不存在
I know you wanna be there for her.
我知道你是想帮她的
Well,here it is. This is your chance.
好了，这是次机会
Hey. What's up,Ryan?
嘿，Ryan，怎么了？
Jim. - You ever read this before?
- Jim - 你读过这本书吗？
Yeah,it's pretty powerful stuff. - I'll say.
- 读过，写得相当好 - 我也这么认为
Er...Kara mentioned that you were having some thoughts.
呃…Kara说你有些别的想法
I don't think I'm going to be able to er... to do this.
我觉得我可能做不了
Why would you say that...today?
为什么到今天才说这个？
Well,last night I was kinda laying in bed and I couldn't get to sleep.
昨晚我躺在床上无法入睡
So I started thinking about the wedding and the ceremony,
就开始想婚礼和仪式
and about our buying a house and moving in together.
然后是我们买房一起住
And having a kid, and having another kid and then
接着开始一个接一个的生孩子
Christmas and Thanksgiving and spring break.
过了几个圣诞节、感恩节和春假
Going to football games,and then all of a sudden they're graduating.
看几场球赛，然后突然间孩子们就毕业了
They're getting jobs,getting married. And,you know,I'm a grandparent.
他们工作，结婚，接着我就成爷爷了
And then I'm retired. I'm losing my hair,I'm getting fat.
之后我退休，脱发，发福
And then the next thing you know I'm dead.
接下来的你也知道，我就死了
I'm just,like...I can't stop from thinking, what's the point?
我就像是…不能停止去想，这有什么意义？
I mean,what is the point?
意义何在？
The point? - What am I starting here?
- 意义？ - 我为什么要结婚呢？
Jim,it's...marriage.
Jim，这就是婚姻
It's one of the most beautiful things on earth. It's what people aspire to.
这是世界上最美妙的事情 是人们梦寐以求的
You never got married. - That's true.
- 你又没结过婚 - 这倒是
I mean,you never even tried. - Well,it's hard to define try.
- 你甚至从不想去尝试结婚 - 那要看你怎么定义尝试了
I don't know,just you seem happier than all my married friends.
我不知道，只是你看起来比我的已婚朋友们都要开心
Look,Jim,I'm not going to lie to you. Marriage can be a pain in the ass.
Jim，我不想骗你，婚姻是会很可怕
And you're right. This all is just stuff that leads to your eventual demise.
你是对的，这些事情最终都会发生
Yes. - And we're all on running clocks.
- 是啊 - 我们都在时间的河流上流淌着
And they can't be slowed down or paused.
而时间并不会减慢，或者暂停
And...we all end up in the same place. - yeah.
- 最终我们的结局都一样 - 是的
There is no point. - There is no point. That's what I'm saying.
- 没有任何意义 - 没有意义，我就是这个意思
You know,er...
你知道…
I'm not normally the guy you would talk to about stuff like this.
通常情况下你是不会和我探讨这些的
If you think about it...
但你仔细想想
your favourite memories,the most important moments in your life.
你生命中最珍贵的回忆，最重要的瞬间
Were you alone?
那时你是独自一人吗？
No,I guess not.
我觉得不是
Come to think of it,
接着想
last night,the night before your wedding when all this shit is swirling around in your head,
昨晚，婚礼前夜 当你脑中萦绕着这些乱七八糟的东西时
weren't you guys in separate bedrooms?
你们不在一起睡吧？
Yeah,Julie went back to the apartment and I was just by myself in the honeymoon suite.
Julie回公寓了，我自己在蜜月套房睡的
Kinda lonely,huh? - Yes,it was pretty lonely.
- 有点孤独吧？ - 嗯，相当孤独
Life's better with company.
有伴的生活会更好
Yeah... - Everybody needs a co-pilot.
- 是 - 每个人都需要一个副驾驶
That was a nice touch. - Thanks.
- 说的很对 - 谢谢
So er... what's the mood like out there? - It's not good.
- 那么…外面气氛怎么样？ - 不怎么好
She's pretty pissed? - Just upset.
- 她很生气吗？ - 只是很沮丧
What should I do?
我该怎么办？
Go get her.
去找她
I'm such a fuck-up. I love you so much.
我真是混账透顶 我真的很爱你
Will you be my co-pilot?
你愿意当我的副驾驶，陪伴我吗？
Yes. Yes.
当然
Welcome home.
欢迎回家
OK,this is your stop.
好了，到了
When am I gonna see you? - You're just gonna have to come visit.
- 我们什么时候能再见？ - 来家里找我就行
Oh...so settled.
安顿下来了
You're not gonna change on me,are you? - No. Same guy. Just one address.
- 你不会就这么变了吧？ - 不会，我还是我，只是地址固定了
This is your final boarding call for Flight 3972 to Chicago.
飞往芝加哥的3972次航班就要起飞了
Right. Call me when you get lonely.
好吧，寂寞的时候记得给我打电话
I'm lonely.
我寂寞了
Some guy sits in a conference room somewhere
员工们坐在会议室里
and our server routes his session to one of our termination engineers.
终结工程师通过服务器来解雇他们
"Termination engineers"? Really?
“终结工程师”？真的？
I preferred "terminators" but it bumped with Legal.
我更喜欢叫“终结者”，不过怕有法律纠纷
Can't imagine why.
难以想象
The workflow takes them through anything from a standard dismissal to a violent aggressor.
他们接触的员工，从心平气和的到咄咄逼人的都有
What are they doing now,practising?
他们现在在干什么，练习吗？
Beta testing,role-playing. We go live at the end of the month.
测试，角色扮演 这个月底真正开始
Kyle,you're running through the events too quickly.
Kyle，你进行的太快了
Give them time to acknowledge each statement. It's a legal thing.
给他们点时间接受每一句话，不要引起法律纠纷
Ryan? - Mm? Oh. Yeah. There's more?
- Ryan？ - 哦，还有？
This is ridiculous.
真是荒谬
Legal's starting to come hard at me on this term "terminate"...
“终结”一词可能会引起法律纠纷…
Life to the power of you!
活出你自己的精彩！
Ladies and gentlemen. Put your hands together for today's challenge speaker,
女士们先生们，掌声欢迎今天的演讲挑战者
Mr Ryan Bingham
Ryan Bingham先生
Go get 'em.
好好表现
Last year I flew 350,000 miles.
去年我飞了35万英里
The moon is 250.
月球离地球也只不过25万英里
I want you to imagine for a second that you're carrying a backpack.
想象一下你背着一个背包
I want you to feel the straps on your shoulders
感觉一下肩膀承受的重量
You feel 'em?
感觉到了吗？
Now I want you to pack it with all the stuff that you have in your life.
现在把人生里所有的东西都装进去
Start with the little things - the things on shelves and in drawers.
从小东西开始，架子上的，抽屉里的
Excuse me.
抱歉
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈的在干什么？
Relax. We'll have your next guest out in one sec.
大家不要慌，马上请出下一位演讲者
Hey,you gotta sign. - OK.
- 你得签个名 - 好的
OK,thank you.
谢谢
Hey,you forgot to give me your Hertz No.1 Gold Card!
嘿，你的Hertz金卡还没给我呢！ （Hertz：美国汽车租赁巨头）
So I was in the neighbourhood.
我恰好在附近
Hey,honey,who's at the door? - Just somebody who's lost.
- 亲爱的，谁来了？ - 有个人迷路了
Alex?
Alex？
What were you thinking, showing up at my door like that?
你怎么想的，那样就来我家找我了？
What do you mean? I wanted to see you. I didn't know you had a family.
什么意思？ 我想见你，我不知道你有家人
Why didn't you tell me that?
为什么不告诉我？
Sorry I ruined your evening but you could have screwed things up for me.
抱歉我毁了你那个夜晚 但你差点把我的生活全毁了
That's my family. That's my real life.
那是我的家人，是我真正的生活
I thought I was a part of your real life.
我以为我是你真正生活的一部分
I thought we signed up for the same thing.
我还以为我们想法一致呢
Try and help me understand exactly what it is that you signed up for.
和我说说你的想法是什么
I thought our relationship was perfectly clear. I mean...
我觉得我们的关系十分清楚，我是说
you are an escape.
你是我逃避的港湾
You're a break from our normal lives, you're a...
进入到了我的正常生活里，是
a parenthesis.
一段插曲
I'm a parenthesis?
我是插曲？
I mean... what do you want?
我是说…你想怎么样？
Tell me what you want.
告诉我你想怎么样
You don't even know what you want.
你甚至都不知道想要什么
Ryan,I'm a grown-up,OK?
Ryan，我是成年人了，好吗？
So if you would like to see me again, then then give me a call.
如果你想见我，给我打电话
OK?
好吗？
Ladies and gentlemen,we have a special announcement to make.
女士们先生们，我们要宣布一条重要消息
Our pilot has just informed me that we are passing over the city of Dubuque,
机长刚刚告诉我，我们正在杜布桥市上空
which might not mean much to most of you, but means a lot to one of our flyers today.
对大多数人来说可能没什么意义 但对其中一位乘客来说意义重大
Oh,no. - He just hit 10 million miles!
- 不是吧 - 他的飞行里程达到了1千万公里！
Congratulations. - Such an amazing accomplishment.
- 恭喜 - 了不起的成绩
You must be very excited.
你一定很激动吧
Hi,Captain. - Captain.
- 机长好
That seat taken?
旁边有人吗？
No. No.
没有
You're the youngest yet to hit 10 mil.
你是达到1千万英里最年轻的人
Don't know where you found the time.
不知道你怎么有时间做到的
Yeah. I don't know.
我也不知道
Here you go.
这个给你
Seventh card we've made.
我们制作的第七张卡
Small club.
很少有人得到
We really appreciate your loyalty.
我们由衷感谢你的忠诚
You know how many times I thought about this moment?
你知道我憧憬过多少次这个时刻吗？
Played out the conversation that you and I would have right here.
想象我和你可能的对话
Really?
真的吗？
What did you want to say?
你想说什么？
You know,I don't remember.
我不记得了
That's all right. It happens to all of us.
没关系，我们都会这样
So where are you from?
你是哪里人
I'm from here.
我的家就在云端
Hello,Mr Bingham.
Bingham先生，您好
How did you know it was me?
你怎么知道是我？
This is your dedicated line. We reserve them for our most loyal and appreciated flyers.
这是您的专线，我们为顶级会员专门提供的
I'd like to transfer some of my miles. Can I open up an account to Jim and Julie Miller?
我想转换一些我的里程数 我可以给Jim和Julie Miller开个账户吗？
Certainly. How many miles would you like to transfer?
当然可以，要转换多少英里呢？
How many miles does it take to circle the globe?
环球旅游需要多少英里？
We have our round-the-world tickets. They're 500,000 miles each.
我们有环球旅游的套票，每张需要50万英里
That'd be fine. - Got a second?
- 不错 - 有时间吗？
I'll call you back.
我再打给你
What happened to you yesterday? I was trying to get hold of you.
你昨天怎么了？ 我一直在找你
I was some personal stuff. What's going on?
有些私事，怎么了？
Do you remember Karen Barnes,
还记不记得Karen Barnes
part of a 30-person reduction a few weeks back in Wichita?
几周前在威奇托裁掉的一个人
Natalie fired her. - Fired dozens of people a day. I...
- Natalie裁的她 - 那天裁了几十人，我
She killed herself - jumped off a bridge.
她自杀了，从桥上跳下去的
Fuck.
操
I need to know if you remember any woman that gave you any signals,
我需要知道是不是有人给过你们暗示
depression... - They're all depressed. We're firing them.
- 表现的很沮丧 - 他们都很沮丧，我们是在炒他们
Hey,I need to ask you this stuff,OK? - No,I don't remember anything.
- 嘿，我可得问清楚，配合一下吧 - 我不记得了
You never think that they're...
永远也想不到他们
You don't remember any woman that gave you any signals?
不记得有任何人给过你暗示了？
Anything at all,Ryan? - No,nothing stands out.
- 任何线索都行，Ryan - 没有任何线索
Is Natalie all right? - Natalie quit.
- Natalie还好吗？ - Natalie辞职了
She quit? - Text message.
- 她辞职了？ - 通过短信
Fucking nice,right? No-one's got any manners any more.
真他妈的爽快，对吧，现在人越来越没礼貌了
Did she say where she was going? - No. She was a little upset.
- 她有没有说过要去哪？ - 没有，她有点消沉
I should give her a call.
我该给她打个电话
I need you back in the air.
我需要你回来工作
Hey. Did you hear what I said? I thought you'd be thrilled about that.
听到我说的了没？ 我本以为你会很兴奋呢
It's fine. What about the videoconferencing?
好吧，那视频方式怎么办？
CTC is going to pause the new media front. They're gonna give it some more thought.
反恐中心叫停了，他们要再考虑考虑
We are gonna get our workhorses back in the air doing what they do best,OK?
我们要让员工回来，继续飞行出差，懂吗？
How long are you sending me out?
你要派我出去多久？
We're gonna let you sail and sail. You send us a postcard if you ever get there.
多久都行，别忘了到了之后记张明信片回来
So what happened?
发生什么了？
How exactly do you mean?
你是什么意思？
You graduated top of your class.
你以班级第一的成绩毕业
You seemed to have your pick of employment,including here.
你应该有很多选择，包括这里
Instead you went to Omaha to fire people for a living?
但你却去了奥马哈，以解雇别人为生？
It's challenging work. - I'll say!
- 那是个有挑战性的工作 - 我也这么认为
I can't imagine doing that, day in,day out.
我简直不能想象，日复一日地做这个
Not in this climate.
和这边完全不同
I followed a boy.
我跟男朋友去的
I guess everybody does that at one point or another.
每个人大概都会有这样那样的理由吧
This guy says I'd be lucky to have you.
这个人写道，能聘用你会是我们的荣幸
To whom it may concern.
致开启者
I can't even count the number of people I've fired in my lifetime.
我都记不清一生之中解雇过多少人了
So many that I've actually forgotten what it's like to hire somebody.
以至于我已经淡忘了聘用别人的感觉
We've never met,but I know you'd be lucky to have Natalie Keener.
我们素未谋面 但我很清楚聘用Natalie Keener会是你的荣幸
My advice? Take her and don't look back.
我的建议？毫不犹豫地聘用他
She'll be the best decision you've made in a long time.
她会是你的最好选择
I sure hope he's right.
我希望他是对的
Well,I don't have a lot of hope,
我没有很多期望
and I really don't know when it's gonna get better.
也真的不知道情况会不会变好
There's a lot of people unemployed.
很多人都失业了
And I really don't know when there's gonna be light at the end of the tunnel.
真的不知道这种日子什么时候才能到头
I can't find much to talk about.
没有什么好说的
Talk about being proud. I'm proud of my kids.
要说值得骄傲的，我为我的孩子骄傲
I think the anger comes from the fact that I just wasn't needed any more.
我觉得愤怒源于我不再被需要这个事实
I would say,you know,uh...
我会说，呃...
without my friends and my family,
如果没有我的朋友和家人
I wouldn't have made it.
我不可能撑得住
It would have been a lot tougher if I'd had to make it on my own.
我一个人承担，担子当然会很重
When I wake up in the morning and I look over and I see my wife,
当我每天早晨醒来，看到身旁的妻子的时候
that gives me the sense of purpose.
我立刻有了生活的勇气
It's not all about the money. Money can keep you warm.
并不都是钱的原因，钱能使你温暖
It pays your heating bills. It can buy you a blanket.
能付暖气费，能买毛地毯
But it doesn't keep you as warm as when my husband holds me.
但它给不了我丈夫所给的温暖
Let me get up. Let me get out. Let me find something.
我能起床，出去，找别的工作
So my kids are my purpose. My family.
孩子，家庭是我的动力
Tonight most people will be welcomed home by jumping dogs and squealing kids.
人们今晚回家 迎接他们的是蹦跳的宠物，欢闹的孩子
Their spouses will ask about their day and tonight they'll sleep.
配偶们会关心他们一天的情况，然后一起睡去
The stars will wheel forth from their daytime hiding places.
白昼逝去，繁星闪烁
And one of those lights, slightly brighter than the rest,
天空中一道光芒格外闪亮
will be my wing tip passing over.
那会是我的机翼划过的痕迹
Hi,Jason. My name is Kevin. And I recently lost my job.
Jason你好，我叫Kevin，最近失业了 （Jason Reitman 本片导演）
I wrote this song as sort of a statement about uncertainty
为了表达对未来的焦虑以及不确定
and having a certain amount of anxiety about the future.
我写了这首歌
So maybe you can use it in your movie.
希望能对你的电影有用